<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <str key="home">Home page</str>
  <str key="savedesktop_wiki">SaveDesktop wiki</str>
  <str key="wiki_description">SaveDesktop is a simple application written in Python using GTK and LibAdwaita libraries. This wiki is used to explain some of the features of the application (e.g. synchronization between computers).

This wiki can be translated via [Weblate](https://hosted.weblate.org/projects/vikdevelop/savedesktop-github-wiki/). The translation files can be found in [`translations/wiki`](https://github.com/vikdevelop/SaveDesktop/tree/main/translations/wiki).

For easier navigation, there is a sidebar where you can switch between languages and pages. In addition to the sidebar, you can view the individual pages below:</str>
  <str key="select_language">Select language</str>
  <str key="localize-wiki">Localize SaveDesktop wiki (via Weblate)</str>
  <str key="github_issues">_If you have any questions, you can use GitHub issues._</str>
  <str key="periodic_saving">Periodic Saving</str>
  <str key="how_it_works">### How it works?</str>
  <str key="pb_desc">In addition to manual saves, SaveDesktop also allows you to save your desktop configuration periodically. You can choose from the following options:</str>
  <str key="pb_options">- **Daily**: 
  - After logging into the system, SaveDesktop starts in the background and backs up the configuration. If you then log back in this day, it will not do it again, because it has already been created for that day.
- **Weekly**:
  - SaveDesktop performs a configuration backup every Monday if "Weekly" is selected. If the computer is not running on that day, SaveDesktop does not do it the next day.
- **Monthly**:
  - If "Monthly" is selected, SaveDesktop makes the backup on the first day of the month, e.g. May 1, June 1, December 1, etc. As with "Weekly", if the computer is not running on that day, SaveDesktop does not perform it the next day.
- **Never**:
  - Nothing's happening</str>
  <str key="pb_location">### Where are the periodic saving files stored?
Default directory for periodic saving is `/home/user/Downloads/SaveDesktop/archives`, but you can choose custom directory.</str>
  <str key="pb_filename_title">### Filename format</str>
  <str key="pb_filname_desc">If you want to give a filename format for periodic saving files other than `Latest_configuration`, it is possible, even with spaces. Since version 2.9.6, variable `{}` doesn't work for setting the today date because now, in every periodic saving, the original backup file is overwritten.</str>
  <str key="save_installed_flatpaks_title">Save installed Flatpak apps and install them from list</str>
  <str key="save_flatpak_intro">Since version 2.5, SaveDesktop allows you to save installed Flatpak applications and install them from a list. So how does it work?</str>
  <str key="saving_flatpaks">### Saving installed Flatpak applications
It is possible to save a list of installed Flatpak applications installed in the system directory /var/lib/flatpak/app and the home directory ~/.local/share/flatpak/app. The list of installed Flatpak applications in the configuration archive is marked as installed_flatpaks.sh for the system directory and installed_user_flatpaks.sh for the home directory.</str>
  <str key="installing_flatpaks">### Installing Flatpak applications from the list
After importing the saved configuration file and logging back in, **the Flatpak applications will start installing in the background.**</str>
  <str key="synchronization_between_computers_title">Synchronization between computers in the network</str>
  <str key="how_to_set_up_it">## How to set up it?</str>
  <str key="whats_your_needing"> ### What's your needing?</str>
  <str key="on_computer_1">**On computer 1:**
- manually assign the IP addresses of your devices that you want to sync so that the IP address does not change every time the computer is turned on. It is possible to set it via:</str>
  <str key="router_settings">**Router settings:**
  - [for Asus routers](https://www.asus.com/support/FAQ/1000906/)
  - [for Tp-link routers](https://www.tp-link.com/us/support/faq/170/)
  - [for Tenda routers](https://www.tendacn.com/faq/3264.html)
  - [for Netgear routers](https://kb.netgear.com/25722/How-do-I-reserve-an-IP-address-on-my-NETGEAR-router)
  - if you don't have the above routers, open your router settings (URL: [192.168.1.1](http://192.168.1.1) or related) and search in the DHCP server section something in the shape of "Manually assign an IP to the DHCP list" or "Static IP", etc.</str>
  <str key="sys_config_print">  **`system-config-printer` package:**
  - if you don't want to set the IP address manually from the router interface, and if you have a printer and have installed `system-config-printer` package, check if you ticked the option "Shared" by clicking the Printer tab on the header bar. If not, please tick it and reboot the system. [Here](https://github-production-user-asset-6210df.s3.amazonaws.com/83600218/272054218-ff17c19b-98f5-41fe-8f34-40de275f0da4.png) is a screenshot, what it's supposed to look like.</str>
  <str key="on_computer_2">**On computer 2:**
- Check if you are connected to the same network as computer 1.</str>
  <str key="sync_in_savedesktop">### Set synchronization in the SaveDesktop app
On computer 1 and 2, open the SaveDesktop application and switch to the Sync page. On computer 1, click on the button "Set up the sync file", select the synchronization file (your periodic saving file), and select a periodic synchronization interval. Then copy the URL for synchronization, and on computer 2, click on the button "Connect with other computer" and enter the copied URL for synchronization from computer 1.</str>
  <str key="sync_warning">If you want to sync the DE configuration from computer 2 to computer 1, follow the same procedure.

**For the changes to take effect, it is necessary to logout from system**</str>
  <str key="periodic_sync">## Periodic synchronization
You can choose between the following items:
- Daily
- Weekly (synchronization takes place every Tuesday)
- Monthly (synchronization takes place every second day in the month)
- Manually (it is possible to sync configuration from the menu in the header bar by clicking on the three dots)
- Never (nothing's happening)</str>
  <str key="version_warning">**This feature is available from version: `3.2.2`**</str>
  <str key="import_cfg_in_cli_title">Importing configuration in the CLI interface</str>
  <str key="imp_cfg_cli_intro">In addition to importing configuration in the GUI, SaveDesktop also allows you to import configuration in the command line interface (CLI), which you can use in case your desktop environment breaks.</str>
  <str key="imp_cfg_cli_steps">### So how to proceed?
**1. Open a terminal**

You can open it from the applications menu, or by using the Ctrl+Alt+T keyboard shortcut.

**2. Type the command to import the configuration**

Enter the following command in the terminal:
- if you have SaveDesktop installed as a Flatpak package, use the following:

     ```
     flatpak run io.github.vikdevelop.SaveDesktop --import-config /path/to/filename.sd.tar.gz
     ```

- if you have SaveDesktop installed as a Snap or native package, use: 
     ```
     savedesktop --import-config /path/to/filename.sd.tar.gz
     ```</str>
  <str key="imp_cfg_cli_note">**Note**:
- instead of `/path/to/filename.sd.tar.gz`, enter the path to the configuration archive you want to import, for example: `/home/user/Downloads/myconfig.sd.tar.gz`</str>
  <str key="archive_encryption_">Archive encryption</str>
  <str key="archive_encryption_desc">If you want to encrypt the configuration archive, whether for data protection reasons or something else, you can use the archive encryption feature in the SaveDesktop app. So, how does it work, and how to set it up?</str>
  <str key="ac_intro">## How does it work?
If this feature is enabled, SaveDesktop will always ask you to create a password for your new archive of the configuration. The criteria for the password include at least 8 characters, one uppercase letter, one lowercase letter, and one special character. If the password doesn't meet these criteria, it will not be possible to continue saving configuration. </str>
  <str key="ac_warn">&gt; [!WARNING]  
&gt; The periodic saving files are (so far) not available to protect with a password. Encrypted archives are, so far, not possible to use in synchronization.</str>
  <str key="ac_setup">## How to set it up?
In the 3.3 version, the interface has been slightly modified, specifically, periodic saving section is now located under the "More options" button. On the same place, is located archive encryption section. So click on the already mentioned button, and enable Archive encryption switch.</str>
  <str key="saving_cfg_title">Saving configuration</str>
  <str key="saving_cfg_intro">If you prefer command-line interface (CLI) before graphical user interface (GUI), SaveDesktop in addition to saving configuration in the GUI, allows you save configuration in the CLI.</str>
</root>
