<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <str key="home">Kezdőlap</str>
  <str key="periodic_saving">Időszakos mentés</str>
  <str key="periodic_saving_article">### Hogyan működik?
A manuális mentések mellett, a SaveDesktop lehetővé teszi, hogy időnként elmentsd a számítógéped beállításait. A következő lehetőségek közül választhatsz:
- **Naponta**: 
  - Bejelentkezés után a SaveDesktop elindul a háttérben és elmenti a beállításokat. Ha ugyanazon a napon újra belépsz, a mentés nem fut le még egyszer, hiszen arra a napra már készült biztonsági mentés.
- **Hetente**:
  - A SaveDesktop minden hétfőn biztonsági mentést készít. Ha a számítógép nem fut azon a napon, a sAveDesktop nem készít mentést a következő napon.
- **Havonta**:
  - A SaveDesktop a hónap első napján készíti el a biztonsági mentést. Például, május elsején, június elsején, december elsején, stb. Hasonlóan a heti mentéshez, ha a számítógép nem fut az adott napon, az alkalmazás nem készíti el a mentést a következőn.
- **Soha**:
  - Semmi sem történik.

### Hol tárolódnak a biztonsági mentések?
Az időszakos mentések alapértelmezett könyvtára a `/home/user/Letöltések/SaveDesktop/archives`, de választhatsz egyéni könyvtárat is.

### Fájlnév formátum
Ha más nevet akarsz adni a mentéseknek, mint `config_{}`, beállíthatod a fájlnév formátumot.
Az alapértelmezett név a fent említett `config_{}`. A `{}` egy változó a SaveDesktop alkalmazásban, amely a mai dátumot állítja be. Ha ez a változó nincs a fájlnévben, elérkezik a biztonsági mentés napja és egy biztonsági mentés már létezik a beállított fájlnévvel, az alkalmazás felülírja a meglévőt az új biztonsági mentéssel. Egyébként, új biztonsági mentés fájlt hoz létre az alkalmazás.</str>
  <str key="save_installed_flatpaks_title">Save installed Flatpak apps and install it from list</str>
  <str key="synchronization_between_computers_title">Synchronization between computers in the network</str>
  <str key="synchronization_between_computers_article">## How to set up it?
### What's your needing?
- manually assigned IP addresses of your devices that you want to sync so that the IP address does not change every time the computer is turned on, it is possible to set up in your router settings:
  - [for Asus routers](https://www.asus.com/support/FAQ/1000906/)
  - [for Tp-link routers](https://www.tp-link.com/us/support/faq/170/)
  - [for Tenda routers](https://www.tendacn.com/faq/3264.html)
  - [for Netgear routers](https://kb.netgear.com/25722/How-do-I-reserve-an-IP-address-on-my-NETGEAR-router)
  - if you don't have the above routers, open your router settings (URL: [192.168.1.1](http://192.168.1.1) or related) and search in the DHCP server section something in the shape of "Manually assign an IP to the DHCP list" or "Static IP", etc.
- if you want to select synchronization file from other than home folder, you need to allow access to file in Flatseal app for proper functionality (related to Flatpak (Sandbox) version)
- check if the folder for periodic saving is same as folder for synchronization file
### Set synchronization in SaveDesktop app
On computer 1 and computer 2, open SaveDesktop application and switch to Sync page. On computer 1 click on button "Set up the sync file", select synchronization file and select periodic synchronization interval. Then copy the URL for synchronization and on computer 2, click on button "Connect with other computer" and enter copied URL for synchronization from computer 1.

If you want to sync DE configuration from computer 2 to computer 1, follow the same procedure.

**For the changes to take effect, it is necessary to logout from system**

## Periodic synchronization
You can choose between the following items:
- Daily
- Weekly (synchronization takes place every Tuesday)
- Monthly (synchronization takes place every second day in the month)</str>
  <str key="pages">Oldalak:</str>
  <str key="github_issues">_Ha bármi kérdésed lenne, használd a Github Issues-t._</str>
  <str key="save_installed_flatpaks_article">Since version 2.5, SaveDesktop allows you to save installed Flatpak applications and install them from a list. So how does it work?

### Saving installed Flatpak applications
It is only possible to save a list of Flatpak applications installed in the system directory `/var/lib/flatpak/app`, not in the home directory `~/.local/share/flatpak/app`. In the saved configuration archive, the list of installed Flatpak applications is labeled as `installed_flatpaks.sh`.

### Installing Flatpak applications from the list
After importing the saved configuration file and logging back in, **the Flatpak applications will start installing in the background.**</str>
  <str key="wiki_description">SaveDesktop is a simple application written in Python using GTK and LibAdwaita libraries. This wiki is used to explain some of the features of the application (e.g. synchronization between computers).

This wiki can be translated via [Weblate](https://hosted.weblate.org/projects/vikdevelop/savedesktop-github-wiki/). The translation files can be found in [`translations/wiki`](https://github.com/vikdevelop/SaveDesktop/tree/main/translations/wiki).

For easier navigation, there is a sidebar where you can switch between languages and pages. In addition to the sidebar, you can view the individual pages below:</str>
  <str key="select_language">Nyelv kiválasztása</str>
  <str key="savedesktop_wiki">SaveDesktop wiki</str>
  <str key="localize-wiki">Honosítsd a SaveDesktop wiki oldalt (a Weblate-n)</str>
</root>
