<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
  <str key="periodic_saving">定期保存</str>
  <str key="pb_desc">除了手动保存，SaveDesktop也允许您定期保存桌面环境配置。您可从以下选项中进行选择：</str>
  <str key="pb_options">- **每天**：
- 当您登录进系统后，SaveDesktop将开始在后台对配置进行备份。当您在同一天再次登录系统时，备份工作将不会重复进行，因为当日的备份文件已被创建。
- **每周**：
- 如果您选择“每周备份”，那么SaveDesktop将在每周一进行备份。如果您周一没有登录系统，那么SaveDesktop也不会在下一次您登录系统时备份。
- **每月**：
- 如果您选择“每月备份”，那么SaveDesktop将在每月的第一天进行备份，例如：5月1日，6月1日，12月1日等。正如“每周备份”那样，如果您在当月第一天没有登录系统，那么SaveDesktop也不会在下一次您登录系统时备份。
- **从不**：
- 无事发生。</str>
  <str key="pb_location">### 定期备份的文件保存在哪里？
定期备份的存档路径默认在`/home/user/Downloads/SaveDesktop/archives`，但您可以自定义路径。</str>
  <str key="pb_filename_title">### 文件名格式</str>
  <str key="pb_filname_desc">如果您不想用`Latest_configuration`这一文件名，而使用一种文件名格式，这其实也是可行的，甚至可以包含空格。 自2.9.6版本之后，变量`{}`不再为当前日期进行设置，因为在定期备份中，原始备份将被覆盖。</str>
  <str key="synchronization_between_computers_title">通过网络在不同计算机中同步</str>
  <str key="periodic_sync">## 定期同步
您可从以下方案中选择:
- 每日
- 每周（在每个周二会进行同步）
- 每月（在每月第二天会进行同步）
- 手动（可手动点击标题栏的三点按钮进行手动同步）
- 从不（无事发生）</str>
  <str key="save_installed_flatpaks_title">保存已安装的Flatpak应用并通过列表进行安装</str>
  <str key="save_flatpak_intro">自2.5版本以后，SaveDesktop允许您保存已安装的Flatpak应用，并支持通过列表安装Flatpak应用。那么它是如何工作的呢？</str>
  <str key="saving_flatpaks">### 保存已安装的Flatpak应用
为已安装的Flatpak应用建立列表是可行的。列表将读取系统安装路径/var/lib/flatpak/app和用户安装路径~/.local/share/flatpak/app中的应用，而保存好的列表将位于存档文件中的installed_flatpaks.sh和installed_user_flatpaks.sh，它们同样分别对应系统安装和用户安装。</str>
  <str key="installing_flatpaks">### 从列表安装Flatpak应用
当完成导入并重新登录后，**Flatpak应用将在后台自动安装。**</str>
  <str key="version_warning">**自`3.2.2`版本起，该功能已实现。**</str>
  <str key="import_cfg_in_cli_title">导入配置</str>
  <str key="imp_cfg_cli_intro">除了通过图形界面导入配置，SaveDesktop也允许您通过命令行界面（CLI）导入配置，当您的桌面环境受损时，这也许会很有用。</str>
  <str key="imp_cfg_cli_steps">### 那么该如何实现呢?
**1. 打开一个终端**

您可通过应用菜单，或者通过快捷键比如Ctrl+Alt+T来打开。

**2. 输入命令以导入配置**

在终端里输入以下命令:
- 如果您通过Flatpak安装了SaveDesktop，则输入：

     ```
     flatpak run io.github.vikdevelop.SaveDesktop --import-config /path/to/filename.sd.tar.gz
     ```

- 如果您通过Snap或本地包安装，则输入：
     ```
     savedesktop --import-config /path/to/filename.sd.tar.gz
     ```</str>
  <str key="imp_cfg_cli_note">**请注意**:
- 应当输入您想导入的配置文件的实际路径以取代`/path/to/filename.sd.tar.gz`，比如：`/home/user/Downloads/myconfig.sd.tar.gz`</str>
  <str key="archive_encryption_">Archive encryption</str>
  <str key="archive_encryption_desc">If you want to encrypt the configuration archive, whether for data protection reasons or something else, you can use the archive encryption feature in the SaveDesktop app. So, how does it work, and how to set it up?</str>
  <str key="ac_intro">## How does it work?
If this feature is enabled, SaveDesktop will always ask you to create a password for your new archive of the configuration. The criteria for the password include at least 12 characters, one uppercase letter, one lowercase letter, and one special character. If the password doesn't meet these criteria, it will not be possible to continue saving configuration. </str>
  <str key="ac_warn">&amp;gt; [!WARNING]  
&amp;gt; The periodic saving files are (so far) not available to protect with a password. Encrypted archives are, so far, not possible to use in synchronization.</str>
  <str key="ac_setup">## How to set it up?
In the 3.3 version, the interface has been slightly modified, specifically, periodic saving section is now located under the "More options" button. On the same place, is located archive encryption section. So click on the already mentioned button, and enable Archive encryption switch.</str>
  <str key="saving_cfg_title">Saving configuration</str>
  <str key="saving_cfg_intro">If you prefer command-line interface (CLI) before graphical user interface (GUI), SaveDesktop in addition to saving configuration in the GUI, allows you save configuration in the CLI.</str>
  <str key="save_cfg_outro">When using this method, it uses parameters from the GUI, specifically parameters from the periodic saving mode, such as filename format and selected folder for periodic saving files. You can save the configuration with this method whenever you want, regardless of the selected periodic saving interval.</str>
  <str key="enc">The archive will be saved as a ZIP archive (because Tar doesn't support the password protection feature), and if you want to extract it, you will be asked to enter the password that you used in the saving configuration process. The same applies in the case of configuration import.

If you forgot the password, it will not possible to extract the archive and use it in the importing configuration process.</str>
  <str key="set_up_first_computer">## Setting up synchronization in the SaveDesktop app
On the first computer:
1. Open the SaveDesktop app
2. On the Sync page, click on the "Set up the sync file" button and then on the "Change" button
3. Click on "Periodic saving" and select the folder that is synchronized with your cloud storage as a periodic saving folder
4. If the periodic saving file does not exist, click on the Create button</str>
  <str key="rclone">&lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rclone&lt;/b&gt;&lt;p&gt;(for other desktop environments)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Install Rclone&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo -v ; curl https://rclone.org/install.sh | sudo bash&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Setup Rclone by using this command, which creates the cloud drive folder, sets up Rclone and mounts the folder
      &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;mkdir -p ~/drive &amp;amp;&amp;amp; rclone config create drive your-cloud-drive-service &amp;amp;&amp;amp; nohup rclone mount drive: ~/drive --vfs-cache-mode writes &amp;amp; echo "The drive has been mounted successfully"&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;* Instead of `your-cloud-drive-service` use the name of your cloud drive service, such as `drive` (for Google Drive), `onedrive`, `dropbox`, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Allow access to the created folder in the [Flatseal app](https://flathub.org/apps/com.github.tchx84.Flatseal).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/details&gt;
  </str>
  <str key="set_up_second_computer">On the second computer:
1. Open the SaveDesktop app
2. Go to the Sync page and click the "Connect to the cloud storage" button.
3. Click on the "Select cloud drive folder" button and select the folder that is synced with the same cloud storage as the first computer.
4. Select the periodic synchronization interval, because if you leave that to Never, the synchronization doesn't work.

To set up bidirectional synchronization, make sure you have the same cloud folder selected in the "Connect to cloud storage" dialog on the first computer, the periodic synchronization interval selected, and the "Bidirectional synchronization" switch enabled.
</str>
  <str key="gnome_online_accounts">&lt;details&gt;
    &lt;summary&gt;&lt;b&gt;GNOME Online Accounts&lt;/b&gt;&lt;p&gt;(for GNOME, Cinnamon, COSMIC (Old) and Budgie desktop environments)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/summary&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Open the GNOME Settings&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Go to the Online Accounts section and select your cloud drive service&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/vikdevelop/SaveDesktop/webpage/wiki/synchronization/screenshots/OnlineAccounts_en.png"&gt;
    
  &lt;/details&gt;
  </str>
  <str key="requirements">#### Requirements
- You must have a folder created that will sync with your cloud storage on each computer you want to sync. This can be done using:</str>
</root>
