<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
    
    <id>io.github.vikdevelop.SaveDesktop</id>
    <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.vikdevelop.SaveDesktop.desktop</launchable>
    <name>SaveDesktop</name>
    <summary>Save the current configuration of your desktop environment</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="cs_CZ">Uložte aktuální konfiguraci vašeho desktopového prostředí</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="fr_FR">Sauvegarder la configuration actuelle de votre environnement de bureau</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="pt_BR">Salvar a configuração atual do seu ambiente desktop</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="it_IT">Salva la configurazione corrente del tuo ambiente desktop</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="nl_NL">Sla de huidige voorkeuren van uw werkomgeving op</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="ar_EG">احفظ التخصيصات الحالية لبيئة سطح المكتب الخاص بك</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="ru_RU">Сохранить текущую конфигурацию окружения рабочего стола</summary>
    <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
    <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
    <developer_name>vikdevelop</developer_name>
    
    <description>
      <p>Would you like to save your current configuration including themes, icons, wallpapers, all desktop environment settings, extensions and so on? SaveDesktop can help you with that. Just one click and you have your configuration saved.</p>
      <p>Supported desktop environments: GNOME, Cosmic, Xfce, Budgie, Pantheon, MATE and Cinnamon</p>
    </description>
    <!-- from translations/cs.json -->
    <description xml:lang="cs_CZ">
      <p>Chtěli byste uložit aktuální konfiguraci zahrnující témata, ikony, tapety, všechna nastavení desktopového prostředí, rozšíření a podobně? S tím vám pomůže program SaveDesktop. Stačí jedno kliknutí a máte konfiguraci uloženou.</p>
      <p>Podporovaná desktopová prostředí: GNOME, Cosmic, Xfce, Budgie, Pantheon, MATE a Cinnamon</p>
    </description>
    <!-- from translations/fr.json -->
    <description xml:lang="fr_FR">
      <p>Vous souhaitez sauvegarder votre configuration actuelle, y compris les thèmes, les icônes, les fonds d'écran, tous les paramètres de l'environnement de bureau, les extensions, etc. SaveDesktop peut vous aider. Un simple clic et votre configuration est sauvegardée.</p>
      <p>Environnements de bureau pris en charge : GNOME, Cosmic, Xfce, Budgie, Pantheon, MATE et Cinnamon</p>
    </description>
    <!-- from translations/pt_BR.json -->
    <description xml:lang="pt_BR">
      <p>Gostaria de salvar sua configuração atual, incluindo temas, ícones, papéis de parede, todas as configurações do ambiente desktop, extensões e assim por diante? SaveDesktop pode ajudá-lo com isso. Apenas um clique e você terá sua configuração salva.</p>
      <p>Ambientes desktop suportados: GNOME, Cosmic, Xfce, Budgie, Patheon, MATE and Cinnamon</p>
    </description>
    <!-- from translations/it.json -->
    <description xml:lang="it_IT">
      <p>Desideri salvare la tua configurazione corrente inclusi temi, icone, sfondi, tutte le impostazioni dell'ambiente desktop, estensioni e così via? SaveDesktop può aiutarti in questo. Basta un clic e hai la tua configurazione salvata.</p>
      <p>Ambienti desktop supportati: GNOME, Cosmic, Xfce, Budgie, Pantheon, MATE e Cinnamon</p>
    </description>
    <!-- from translations/nl.json -->
    <description xml:lang="nl_NL">
      <p>Wilt u uw huidige voorkeuren (thema's, pictogrammen, bureaubladachtergronden, systeemvoorkeuren, uitbreidingen, etc.) opslaan? SaveDesktop kan u hierbij helpen. Met slechts één muisklik wordt alles opgeslagen.</p>
      <p>Ondersteunde werkomgevingen: GNOME, Cosmic, Xfce, Budgie, Pantheon, MATE and Cinnamon</p>
    </description>
    <!-- from translations/ar.json -->
    <description xml:lang="ar_EG">
      <p>هل ترغب في حفظ التخصيصات الحالي الخاص بك بما في ذلك السمات والرموز والخلفيات وجميع إعدادات بيئة سطح المكتب والإضافات وما إلى ذلك؟ يمكن أن يساعدك SaveDesktop في ذلك. بنقرة واحدة فقط ويتم حفظ التخصيصات الخاص بك.</p>
      <p>بيئات سطح المكتب المدعومة: GNOME, Cosmic, Xfce, Budgie, Pantheon, MATE and Cinnamon</p>
    </description>
    <!-- from translations/ru.json -->
    <description xml:lang="ru_RU">
      <p>Вы хотите сохранить текущую конфигурацию, включая темы, значки, обои, все настройки окружения рабочего стола, расширения и т.д.? SaveDesktop поможет вам в этом. Всего один клик - и ваша конфигурация сохранена.</p>
      <p>Поддерживаемые окружения рабочего стола: GNOME, Cosmic, Xfce, Budgie, Pantheon, MATE, Cinnamon</p>
    </description>
    
    <url type="homepage">https://github.com/vikdevelop/SaveDesktop</url>
    <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/vikdevelop/SaveDesktop/issues</url>
    <url type="translate">https://hosted.weblate.org/projects/vikdevelop/savedesktop/</url>
    
    <screenshots>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/vikdevelop/SaveDesktop/main/flatpak/screenshots/main_window.png</image>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>
    
    <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
    
    <categories>
        <category>Utility</category>
    </categories>
    
    <releases>
      <release version="1.3" date="2023-03-10">
        <description>
          <ul>
            <li>Added Arabic translations, thanks to @fawaz006</li>
            <li>Added Russian translations, thanks to @vorons</li>
            <li>Updated translations</li>
            <li>Added support for MATE DE and using GNOME in Ubuntu distribution</li>
            <li>Added alert message about using spaces in the file name entry</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="1.2" date="2023-03-09">
        <description>
          <ul>
            <li>Added Italian translations, thanks to @albanobattistella</li>
            <li>Added Dutch translations, thanks to @Vistaus</li>
            <li>Added support for Pantheon desktop environment</li>
            <li>Added support for using GNOME on Zorin OS distribution</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="1.1" date="2023-03-08">
        <description>
          <ul>
            <li>Added Portugalese (Brazil) translations, thanks to @fnogcps</li>
            <li>Added French translations, thanks to tachyglossues</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="1.0" date="2023-03-06">
      </release>
    </releases>
    
</component>
