<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
    
    <id>io.github.vikdevelop.SaveDesktop</id>
    <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.vikdevelop.SaveDesktop.desktop</launchable>
    <name>SaveDesktop</name>
    <summary>Save the current configuration of your desktop environment</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="cs_CZ">Uložte aktuální konfiguraci vašeho desktopového prostředí</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="fr_FR">Sauvegarder la configuration actuelle de votre environnement de bureau</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="pt_BR">Salvar a configuração atual do seu ambiente desktop</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="it_IT">Salva la configurazione corrente del tuo ambiente desktop</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="nl_NL">Sla de huidige voorkeuren van uw werkomgeving op</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="ar_SA">احفظ التخصيصات الحالية لبيئة سطح المكتب الخاص بك</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="ru_RU">Сохранить текущую конфигурацию окружения рабочего стола</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="id_ID">Simpan konfigurasi lingkungan desktop Anda saat ini</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="nb_NO">Lagre nåværende oppsett av skrivebordsmiljøet ditt</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="uk_UA">Збережіть поточну конфігурацію середовища робочого столу</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="hu_HU">Mentsd el az asztali környezeted jelenlegi konfigurációját</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="es_ES">Guarda la configuración actual de tu entorno de escritorio</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="tr_TR">Masaüstünün şuanki ayarlarını kayıt et</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="de_DE">Speichern Sie die aktuelle Konfiguration Ihrer Desktop-Umgebung</summary>
    <summary xml:lang="zh_CN">保存桌面环境的当前配置</summary>
    <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
    <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
    <developer_name>vikdevelop</developer_name>
    
    <description>
      <p>SaveDesktop lets you save your current configuration (themes, icons, wallpapers, all desktop environment settings, extensions, etc.) with one click.</p>
      <p xml:lang="cs_CZ">SaveDesktop umožňuje uložit aktuální konfiguraci (motivy, ikony, tapety, všechna nastavení prostředí, rozšíření atd.) jedním kliknutím.</p>
      <p xml:lang="fr_FR">SaveDesktop vous permet de sauvegarder votre configuration actuelle (thèmes, icônes, fonds d'écran, tous les paramètres de l'environnement de bureau, les extensions, en un seul clic.</p>
      <p xml:lang="pt_BR">Gostaria de salvar sua configuração atual, incluindo temas, ícones, papéis de parede, todas as configurações do ambiente desktop, extensões e assim por diante? SaveDesktop pode ajudá-lo com isso. Apenas um clique e você terá sua configuração salva.</p>
      <p xml:lang="it_IT">Desideri salvare la tua configurazione corrente inclusi temi, icone, sfondi, tutte le impostazioni dell'ambiente desktop, estensioni e così via? SaveDesktop può aiutarti in questo. Basta un clic e hai la tua configurazione salvata.</p>
      <p xml:lang="nl_NL">Wilt u uw huidige voorkeuren (thema's, pictogrammen, bureaubladachtergronden, systeemvoorkeuren, uitbreidingen, etc.) opslaan? SaveDesktop kan u hierbij helpen. Met slechts één muisklik wordt alles opgeslagen.</p>
      <p xml:lang="ar_EG">هل ترغب في حفظ التخصيصات الحالي الخاص بك بما في ذلك السمات والرموز والخلفيات وجميع إعدادات بيئة سطح المكتب والإضافات وما إلى ذلك؟ يمكن أن يساعدك SaveDesktop في ذلك. بنقرة واحدة فقط ويتم حفظ التخصيصات الخاص بك.</p>
      <p xml:lang="ru_RU">Вы хотите сохранить текущую конфигурацию, включая темы, значки, обои, все настройки окружения рабочего стола, расширения и т.д.? SaveDesktop поможет вам в этом. Всего один клик - и ваша конфигурация сохранена.</p>
      <p xml:lang="id_ID">SaveDesktop memungkinkan Anda menyimpan konfigurasi saat ini (tema, ikon, wallpaper, semua pengaturan lingkungan desktop, ekstensi, dll.) dengan satu klik.</p>
      <p xml:lang="nb_NO">SaveDesktop lar deg lagre ditt nåværende oppsett (drakter, ikoner, bakgrunnsbilder, alle skrivebordsmiljøinnstillinger, utvidelser, osv.) med ett klikk.</p>
      <p xml:lang="uk_UA">SaveDesktop дозволяє зберегти поточну конфігурацію (теми, значки, шпалери, всі налаштування середовища робочого столу, розширення тощо) одним клацанням миші.</p>
      <p xml:lang="hu_HU">SaveDesktop lehetővé teszi, hogy egy gombnyomással elmentsd a jelenlegi konfigurációdat (témákat, ikonokat, háttereket, az összes asztali környezeti beállítást, kiegészítéseket, stb.).</p>
      <p xml:lang="es_ES">SaveDesktop te permite guardar tu configuración actual (temas, iconos, fondos de pantalla, todos los ajustes del entorno del escritorio, extensiones, etc.) con un solo clic.</p>
      <p xml:lang="tr_TR">SaveDesktop senin suanki ayarlarını(temalar,iconlar,duvar kağıtları, tüm masaüstü ortam ayları , eklentiler , vb.) tek tıkla kaydetmene izin verir.</p>
      <p xml:lang="de_DE">Mit SaveDesktop können Sie Ihre aktuelle Konfiguration (Designs, Symbole, Hintergrundbilder, alle Einstellungen der Desktop-Umgebung, Erweiterungen usw.) mit einem Klick speichern.</p>
      <p xml:lang="zh_CN">SaveDesktop 可让您一键保存当前配置（主题、图标、壁纸、所有桌面环境设置、扩展等）。</p>
    </description>
    
    <url type="homepage">https://github.com/vikdevelop/SaveDesktop</url>
    <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/vikdevelop/SaveDesktop/issues</url>
    <url type="translate">https://hosted.weblate.org/projects/vikdevelop/savedesktop/</url>
    
    <screenshots>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/vikdevelop/SaveDesktop/main/flatpak/screenshots/main_window.png</image>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/vikdevelop/SaveDesktop/main/flatpak/screenshots/import_page.png</image>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>
    
    <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
    
    <categories>
        <category>Utility</category>
    </categories>
          
    <releases>
       <release version="2.8" date="2023-08-04">
           <description>
               <ul>
                   <li>Added option for choosing file name format for periodic saving (information about how it works can be found in the Wiki article about periodic saving, it is available under Learn More button under the periodic saving section)</li>
                   <li>Now, it is possible to choose items that will be included in the configuration archive. These items include icons, fonts, themes, and backgrounds.</li>
                   <li>Improved menu switcher in the header bar</li>
               </ul>
           </description>
       </release>
       <release version="2.7" date="2023-07-07">
          <description>
            <ul>
              <li>Now, after saving the configuration and opening the folder, the configuration file will be selected automatically, so you don't need to have difficulty searching for the configuration file in the folder.</li>
              <li>Added support for setting the filename with spaces</li>
            </ul>
          </description>
       </release>
       <release version="2.6" date="2023-06-04">
          <description>
            <ul>
              <li>Added option to choosing custom folder for periodic saving</li>
              <li>Importing a configuration from the list is now dependent on selecting a folder for periodic saving</li>
            </ul>
          </description>
       </release>
       <release version="2.5" date="2023-05-28">
          <description>
            <ul>
              <li>Added option for saving installed Flatpak apps (#84) (is possible backup only flatpaks that has been installed on system)</li>
              <li>For storing SaveDesktop app settings (such as filename, window size, etc.) is now using GSettings instead of JSON file</li>
            </ul>
          </description>
       </release>
       <release version="2.4" date="2023-05-08">
          <description>
            <ul>
              <li>Added option for saving configuration to custom directory</li>
            </ul>
            <p>NOTE:</p>
            <p>You can save configuration to more or less to anything regular directory in home folder such as ~/Downloads, ~/Pictures, ~/Documents, ~/Music, etc., but if you want to save configuration e.g. on another hard drive, will be neccessary allow access in Flatseal to work correctly.</p>
          </description>
       </release>
       <release version="2.3.1" date="2023-04-22">
          <description>
            <ul>
              <li>Added new application icon, thanks to @bragefuglseth</li>
              <li>Updated translations</li>
            </ul>
          </description>
       </release>
       <release version="2.3" date="2023-04-19">
          <description>
            <ul>
              <li>Added Chinese (simplified) translations, thanks to @carrothu-cn</li>
              <li>Fixed minor bugs</li>
            </ul>
          </description>
       </release>
       <release version="2.2.2" date="2023-04-13">
          <description>
            <ul>
              <li>Improved saving and importing configuration</li>
              <li>Added link to About Dialog about how periodic saving works (is possible to find it under option "Details")</li>
              <li>Updated translations</li>
            </ul>
          </description>
        </release>
        <release version="2.2" date="2023-04-07">
          <description>
            <p>New application design</p>
            <ul>
              <li>Divided into two pages: Save current configuration and Import saved configuration</li>
              <li>Added option for import from list</li>
              <li>Replaced normal File Chooser Dialog with File Chooser Native: is now possible load configuration from anything directory</li>
              <li>Added option for save Flatpak apps custom permissions</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="2.1" date="2023-04-01">
          <description>
            <ul>
              <li>Added periodic saving (Never, Daily, Weekly and Monthly)</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="2.0" date="2023-03-28">
          <description>
            <ul>
              <li>Added Deutsch translations, thanks to @gimplyworxs</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="1.9" date="2023-03-24">
          <description>
            <ul>
              <li>Added support for KDE Plasma DE</li>
              <li>Added Turkish translations, thanks to @Batmanly</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="1.8" date="2023-03-20">
          <description>
            <ul>
              <li>Added support for drag and drop for import saved configuration (drag is working only from Downloads directory in default)</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="1.7" date="2023-03-16">
        <description>
          <ul>
            <li>Added Spanish translations, thanks to @gallegonovato</li>
            <li>Fixed minor bugs</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="1.6" date="2023-03-13">
        <description>
          <ul>
            <li>Added Hungarian translations, thanks to @danieluhrinyi</li>
            <li>Updated translations</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="1.5" date="2023-03-12">
        <description>
          <ul>
            <li>Added Ukrainian translations, thanks to @Kefir2105</li>
            <li>Added Norwegian (Bokmål) translations, thanks to @comradekingu</li>
            <li>Updated translations</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="1.4" date="2023-03-11">
        <description>
          <ul>
            <li>Added Indonesian translations, thanks to @sekalengrengginang </li>
            <li>Bug fixes</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="1.3" date="2023-03-10">
        <description>
          <ul>
            <li>Added Arabic translations, thanks to @fawaz006</li>
            <li>Added Russian translations, thanks to @vorons</li>
            <li>Updated translations</li>
            <li>Added support for MATE DE and using GNOME in Ubuntu distribution</li>
            <li>Added alert message about using spaces in the file name entry</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="1.2" date="2023-03-09">
        <description>
          <ul>
            <li>Added Italian translations, thanks to @albanobattistella</li>
            <li>Added Dutch translations, thanks to @Vistaus</li>
            <li>Added support for Pantheon desktop environment</li>
            <li>Added support for using GNOME on Zorin OS distribution</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="1.1" date="2023-03-08">
        <description>
          <ul>
            <li>Added Portugalese (Brazil) translations, thanks to @fnogcps</li>
            <li>Added French translations, thanks to tachyglossues</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
      </release>
      <release version="1.0" date="2023-03-06">
      </release>
    </releases>
    
</component>
